JIGAR VYAS

**RESUME** 

JNCIA-JUNOS, JNCIS-ENT, CCNA, CCNP IP Routing

Elk Grove, California, 95757

Github Website Linkedin

#### **Career Statement**

<u>Jigar.vyas@hotmail.com</u>
Cell Number : 213-364-4028

14+ years of experience in diverse networks like Mobility Network, Enterprise Network and in Content Delivery Network with network design, implementation, troubleshooting, developing, POC for new network design and testing it in a lab environment before putting it in production, and maintaining network documentation and network automation.

#### **Technical Skills**

- Switching Protocols (STP/MSTP/VSTP/RSTP, VRRP/HSRP, MC-LAG/VPC/M-LAG, MACSec etc.)
- Routing Protocols (BGP, OSPF/OSPF3, ISIS etc)
- MPLS and Tunneling Protocols (MPLS, RSVP, L2VPN, L3VPN, IPSec, GRE etc)
- Underlay Overlay with VxLAN EVPN
- Network Operation and Configuration
- Root Cause Analysis
- Next-Hop based Dynamic Tunnels (MPLS Over UDP)
- Filter based Forwarding
- Automation and Scripting (Ansible, Python, Flask, Django, Jinja2)
- Network Performance, Management and Monitoring (IPAM, Grafana, Kibana)
- Network Gears (Cisco, Juniper, Arista, Ciena etc)
- Documentation (MkDocs, GitHub Pages, Wiki, Lucid Chart, Visio, Microsoft Office tools)

#### **Employment History**

#### Juniper Networks Inc.

Jan 17th 2023 - Present

Title: Resident Engineer Staff

- Validate new network designs, qualified software images, feature sets and functionalities
- Troubleshoot network issues and perform root cause analysis
- Prepare documentation and perform operational procedures
- Manage communications between customer and internal teams
- Network automation using Ansible, Python, Flask, Jinja2 etc.

Edgio Inc. June 2022 - Jan 2023

Yahoo Inc. as Oath Holding Inc.

May 2016 - June 2022

**Verizon Digital Media Services** 

Mar 2016 - May 2016

Job Title: Senior Network Engineer

- New network topology design and testing with either Juniper, Arista and or Cisco
- Understand user requirements and convert it into network designs and work to translate them into usable configuration
- Responsible for engineering spine and leaf fabric architecture networks, design, testing and implementation. VxLAN and its configuration on Juniper and Arista platform for datacenter redundancy with vendor redundancy

# JIGAR VYAS RESUME

# JNCIA-JUNOS, JNCIS-ENT, CCNA, CCNP IP Routing

Github Website Linkedin

Network automation using Python, Ansible/Napalm, Python Flask

- Build AWS Direct connect connection and put AWS VPCs traffic on it. Build VGW and TGW for AWS traffic redundancy in private network for AWS direct connect failover.
- Using streaming telemetry(gRPC, GNMI) and Telegraf monitor network traffic in monitoring tools like grafana, Kibana etc.
- Network/Data Center Technologies: Juniper Routers (M Series), on BGP OSPF and its ACLs for block and unblock the source and destinations IP based on the network/security requirement
- Configuring router for PoP bring up, circuit Turn ups and creates the LAB environment for testing as well.
- Work with NOC team for troubleshooting the network and customer problems
- Troubleshooting on BGP, OSPF of layer 3 and Layer 2 troubleshooting too
- Routing/Switching: Mx, EX and QFX series platform
- In few PoP Ciena as a backbone(Ciena 6500 and waveserver AI) and so configure the ciena device and ciena automation as well and add ciena in monitoring using GNMI

## Rose International Inc. (USA)

Jan 2016 - Mar 2016

# Client: California water works

#### **Network Engineer**

Jigar.vyas@hotmail.com

Cell Number : 213-364-4028

- Network/Data Center Technologies: Cisco Routers (3900), Cisco Catalyst Switch, Cisco Nexus 5k and 7k Series, Port-Profiles, Routing and Service Profiles.
- Routing/Switching: WAN, LAN, TCP/IP, Spanning Tree, Frame-relay, PPP, Network Address Translation (NAT), Port Address Translation (PAT), Access Control List (ACL), RIP, OSPF, EIGRP, BGP, MPLS, VTP, SNMP, SMTP, Static Routing, VLAN
- Wireless Technologies: PoE, IEEE 802.1x & 802.11, WLAN, WAP, AP, SSID, Aironet.
- Monitoring/APPS: Solarwinds

#### Vodafone West Ltd.

Aug 2009 - Dec 2014

## Sr. Engineer – Network Operation

- Worked on CISCO(ASR 9K,7600 series), Juniper Devices(J,M,Mx series). Also on CPE like Nortel, MROTEK, HP, Huawei routers.
- LAN/WAN network diagnose and troubleshoot on layer 1, 2, 3 problems and informed NOC team for corrective action (Worked with CISCO IOS & JUNIPER JUNOS)
- Responsible for delivery and O&M of Enterprise GGSN networks like Gn, Gy, Gi links.
- Timely site readiness, physical installation of PoP, acceptance test & commissioning of MPLS /Voice network PoP.
- Operation & maintenance of MPLS PoP of Core Enterprise & CEN network and meet customer SLA.
- Responsible for CISCO and JUNIPER RMA process till it's closer. TAC case status update till it's closer.
- Maintain Configuration, Documentation (VISIO's) and Records for Management
- IP backbone readiness for 10G and 100G link integration with DWDM Transport network. And also IP backbone up-gradation to support 100 gig links on the router.
- Distribution and access ring readiness on IP network for 1 gig link with DWDM transport network or on ECI MUX network.
- Performance, capacity & network change management of MPLS network.
- Handling the vendor team and ensuring the network & customer order execution within the timeline in coordination with all stakeholders.

Elk Grove, California, 95757

# JIGAR VYAS RESUME

# JNCIA-JUNOS, JNCIS-ENT, CCNA, CCNP IP Routing

Cell Number : 213-364-4028 <u>Github Website</u> <u>Linkedin</u>

• 3G core back born readiness as per corporate guide line for new roll out.

- Manage spare & necessary tools for corrective maintenance
- Attended training session of OTJNR for juniper routers.

LOBO Staffing (Project : TATA Communication Ltd.)
L1 Data Engineer(wimax RF and IP Engineer)

January 2009 to August 2009

Telsima Communication Pvt. Ltd. Network Operation & Maintenance

Dec 2007 - Feb 2009

Elk Grove,

California, 95757

#### **Certification and Award**

Jigar.vyas@hotmail.com

- Successfully completed CISCO CCNA Certificate, CCNP IP Routing and Juniper JNCIA-JUNOS, JNCIS-ENT
- In Recognition of excellent contribution in Phase II Deployment, O&M of Reliance Communication Wimax Project from Telsima Communication Pvt. Ltd.

## **Education History**

Jan-2015 To Dec-2015 MSEE at NPU, Fremont, California
 June-2003 To June-2006 BEEC at SVMIT, Bharuch, Gujarat, India
 June-2001 To June-2003 Diploma in EC at B.S.Patel Polytechnic University, Mehsana, Gujarat, India

Note: I require sponsorship to work in the USA. My Current VISA status is H1B and I have approved I140 in the green card process.

<u>Declaration</u>: - I hereby declare that the above all information is true to the best of my Knowledge.